Guide to the Biological Safety Advisory Committee, School of Medicine, Yale University, Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Biological Safety Advisory Committee, School of Medicine, Yale University, records
1972-1986
RU 458
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
3.25
(6 boxes)
The records consist of correspondence, reports, articles, minutes, and memoranda documenting the operations of the Yale Biological Safety Advisory Committee.
Yale University. School of Medicine
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 27-D (YRG 27-D), Records of committees of the Yale School of Medicine.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the records is restricted. See Collection Contents for details.
Arrangement
The records are arranged by accession.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of correspondence, reports, articles, minutes, and memoranda documenting the operations of the Yale Biological Safety Advisory Committee.
Biology -- Research -- Safety measures; Yale University. Biological Safety Advisory Committee; Yale University. School of Medicine
- Records, 1972-1984; Accession 1985-A-010
  Conditions Governing Access
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2020
  - Minutes
    - 1976 May - 1983 Mar (Box 1, Folder 1 - 3)
    - 1978 Sep - 1982 Apr (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Agendas, 1976 March - 1983 June (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence with reports & articles
    - 1976 May - Dec (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - 1977 Jan - Mar (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - 1977 Apr - Jun (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - 1977 Jun - Nov (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - 1977 Dec - 1978 Jun (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - 1978 Aug - 1979 Jun (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - 1979 Jul - Dec (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - 1980 Feb - Jun (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Re: Formation of Corrunittee on Virological Hazards & guidelines for research, 1972-1976 (Box 2, Folder 14 - 15)
    - Re: Guidelines for Recombinant DNA research, 1976 July - 1984 February (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - 1976 Nov - 1984 Oct (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Re: infected animals facilities, 1980 July - 1983 June (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Re: Dr. Bhatt's proposal to study ectromelia virus, 1981 September - 1982 June (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Articles Re: Recombinant DNA research, 1976-1977 (Box 3, Folder 20 - 21)
  - Memorandums of Understanding & Agreement and approval sheets
    - Altman, S./McCorckle, G.; Eisenstadt, Jerome; Francke, Bertold; Francke, Uta; Gilbert, Walter (Harvard), 1977-1982 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Weisman, Sherman M. Re: Reclassification of lab (to P3 level), 1976-1979 (Box 5, Folder 35)
    - Principal Investigators, 1977-1980 (Box 5, Folder 36 - 37)
  - Registration
    - 1980 Mar - 1983 May (Box 5, Folder 38 - 39)
- Records, 1974-1986; Accession 1992-A-045
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2022
  - Biological Safety Advisory Committee (BSAC), 1979- 1980 (Box 1, Folder 1 - 2)
  - Biohazards and Safety Conditions, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Safety Manual for Biological Research Laboratories, 1979 July (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Bugetary Matters: Charges for Biosafety services, 1980-1981 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Comments for the Manual DBS, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - BSAC, 1981, 1983-1984 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - BSAC Meetings, 1977 Nov, December (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Safety Guidelines, Revision, to Art Ross, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Yale University Physical Department Safety Manual, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Mandate, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - BSAC Meetings, 1982 February 18 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - BSAC, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Laboratory of Epidemiology and Public Health
    - (LEPH) Biosafety Committee, 1982-1983 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Safety Guidelines for working with Slow Viruses, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Handbook of Operational Procedures, circa 1976 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Biological Safety, 1979-1980 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Dr. Blatt to look at, 1980 August 21 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - BSAC Meeting, 1980 July 16 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - BSAC Meetings, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - DBS and BSAC Notes and Phonecalls, 1980-1982 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Yale Arbovirus Research Unit File Downgrading of agents, 1980-1981 (Box 1, Folder 23)
      - YARU File, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Virus Hazards Committee, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Memo: Adelberg [stops] Bockelman, 1977-1983 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Radiation Safety Procedures, 1977 July (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - A Handbook of Operational Procedures for P-2 and P-3 [Recembiran(?)]: DNA Laboratories, 1978 May (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Management of Chemical Wastes Policy (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Manual, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - LEPH - 9th floor, 1980-1981 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Miscellaneous Material, 1980, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 32)